http://www.archives.org.uk/privacy-policy-.html

Privacy Policy and Notice
ARA GDPR – Privacy Policy and Notice for Members, Suppliers, Partners and Clients
“This policy and notice applies to the use and processing of all personal data by ARA and its subsidiary, ARA Commercial Limited”
Background
New Data Protection Acts (2018) in the UK, Republic of Ireland and some UK dependencies come into force on 25 May 2018. The Acts implement the EU-wide General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Although the UK will be leaving the EU and will then become a ‘third country’ under GDPR, current guidance is that it will continue to observe the fundamentals of the new Regulation. The Archives and Records Association (UK & Ireland) – the ARA or ‘the association’ – will interpret the new legislation in this way until such time as divergence in case law in the EU and/or the UK or future legislative changes require us to do otherwise.
The new Acts extend the definition of personal data into new areas that reflect the digital and other technological realities of the 21st century. As the ARA is a professional membership body, the vast majority of personal data it controls and processes will remain the minimal needed to deliver contracted services. As under previous data protection regimes, this will be limited to: members’ email and physical address details, phone numbers, dates of birth, salary information (to ensure members only pay the annual membership fee appropriate for their income level) and information such as bank and credit/debit card details if members choose to pay their membership fees in this way.
What this means for you as a member
The new legislation replaces previous data protection acts. It broadens the definition of what counts as your personal data, recognises increased data subject (your individual) rights when it comes to their personal data and places more obligations to organisations holding your personal data. One of the rights is a right to be informed, which means we have to give you even more information than we do now about the way in which we use, share and store your personal information. You also have the right to have your personal data corrected or erased and withdraw your consent for us to hold it at any time. Details on how to do this are set out below.
Where we archive any ARA information for future statistical or historical research purposes, which may include personal data, we will do so in conformity with the derogations in Article 89 of the GDPR and the provisions of the new Acts.
All this explains – among other things – why we are publishing our new privacy policy and notice (here), so that you can see how we intend to comply with GDPR, along with information about the increased rights you have in relation to the information we hold on you and our legal basis for processing it. We will always make it clear when we collect your personal data – principally in the membership form when you join and renew your membership each year - and will explain what we intend to do with it.
Legal Bases for Processing Personal Data
The ARA’s principal legal bases for processing personal data of members and ARA staff are explicit consent – through our membership application and annual renewals process – and meeting the requirements of a contract (provision of clearly-identified employer-employee and membership services). We may also rely on the legitimate interests basis for managing the personal data of the ARA’s five salaried staff.
Our membership forms make clear to prospective and renewing members what the explicit consent entails (including, for example, sharing with third parties, how long we will keep members’ data for, and the right of members to change their minds). Further details on these legal bases and what they mean can be found on the UK Information Commissioner’s website: https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/ The ARA employee handbook is being amended to explain formally how the association will process staff personal data.
The ARA is the sole data controller and processor of ARA members’ and ARA staff personal data. Where we work and provide services in partnership with external organisations – eg, suppliers, partners and clients - we will ensure that their privacy statements and policies match our own (see details in our privacy notice here).
Archives and Records Association UK and Ireland
Search
search
REGISTER
LOGIN
HomeAboutContactCommunityVision, Mission, Business PlanConstitutionThe ARA BoardWho’s Who at the ARANations and RegionsSections/Interest GroupsPlay your part with the ARAWhat we doResearch Funding
Archive SurveysEmotional Support GuidesPay Review GroupThe ARA Conference
Archive Service AccreditationResilience IndicatorCampaignsDiversityArchives CardInternational BursariesARA Awards for ExcellenceARC Directory of SuppliersPublications
ARC MagazineOther Useful PublicationsWorkforce ARA Pay ReviewBest Practice GuidelinesAnnual Report & Financial StatementsArchives and Records (ARA Journal)Advertisers InfoNewsARA Today NewsletterARA Today DigestBlogJoinJoin the ARAMembership BenefitsSpecial Offers (members only)Apply OnlineMembership FAQsMembership CategoriesCode of EthicsMembership RenewalWithdraw consent (membership services)Member ReviewARA ShopCareers
Careers in Records ManagementCareers FAQsCareers in ArchivesCareers in Archive ConservationPlacement Opportunities
VolunteeringJobs (ARC Recruitment)ARA VacanciesSalary RecommendationsList of Freelance ConsultantsTraining
Certificate in Archive ConservationOnline Training Session: The Resilience IndicatorARA Events Online Booking How to Organise a Training EventDPC Free placesCPD CPD & the ARA Professional Development ProgrammeQualification levels and benefitsSix Steps to ARA Professional StatusYour questions answeredPDP BlogARA TogetherARA Together Online Community From our Online Community ARA COVID-19 News and PoliciesAdvice and GuidanceFrom the SectorStay Engaged - ARA PDPStay Engaged - Learning OptionsHealth and Wellbeing
Sitemap
Text size A A A
Copyright © 2016 All rights reserved. Privacy Policy | Accessibility | Data Protection | Website Services by EvolvIT
